If I die before I wake... thank you.
Initiation: Silent Night, Deadly Night 4 is a
horror film directed by Brian Yuzna.
A reporter investigating the bizarre death of a woman who leaped from a building in flames finds herself mixed up in
a cult of witches who are making her part of their sacrificial ceremony during the Christmas season.
Fima, played by Maud Adams.
Hank, played by Tommy Hinkley.
Janice, played by Allyce Beasley.
Ricky, played by Clint Howard.
Kim, played by Neith Hunter.
Jane, played by Marjean Holden.
Silent Night, Deadly Night is an American Christmas horror
film series, consisting of seven films.
The first film in the series, Silent Night, Deadly Night (1984), originally titled Slay Ride, tells the story of
Billy, a young man who experiences a psychotic break and goes on a murder spree dressed as Santa Claus.
The film received theatrical distribution from TriStar Pictures, but was pulled from
theaters in November 1984 after a series of protests against the film.
The second film, Silent Night, Deadly Night Part 2 (1987) continues the story of Billy's younger brother, Ricky, who
also goes on a murder spree, and is largely made up of flashbacks featuring footage from the first film.
The third film, Better Watch Out!
released direct-to-video (as were the next two films), concludes the Billy/Ricky storyline, and follows Ricky
as he stalks a clairvoyant blind woman on her way to visit her grandmother for Christmas Eve.
The fourth film, Initiation (1990), departs from the killer Santa storyline, centering on a
feminist cult in Los Angeles, California who are planning a ritual sacrifice.
Directed by Brian Yuzna, the film features special
effects by Screaming Mad George.
The fifth film, The Toy Maker (1991), stars Mickey Rooney as a toy store
proprietor whose brand of toys come to life and murder their owners.
In 2012, a loose remake of the original film, entitled Silent Night, was released
by Anchor Bay Films, starring Jaime King and Malcolm McDowell.
It was the first film in the series to receive a
theatrical release since Part 2 in 1987.
It was followed by another remake, Silent Night, Deadly
Night, which was released in December 2025.
The film explores themes of rape, voodoo, gore, castration, cockroach.
The tone is dark.